hello everyone this is kangsha
gangapuram and you're watching high vis
news
icici lombard posted a mixed set of
numbers for q4
fy22 with a gross direct premium growth
of 4.5 percent qoq to rupees 5000 crores
while net written premium came in at
rupees
3973 crores up to 8.7 percent yoy
however net earned premium was flatish
on a sequential basis at 0.2 percent qoq
to rupees
3317 crores indicating mostly premiums
were written during the end part of the
quarter
income from investment was largely in
line with our estimate at rs 540 crore
expenses were kept under control as
commission declined 21 percent qoq to
rupees 160 crores but claims increased
four percent sequentially two rupees two
thousand three hundred and eighty nine
crores the company thurs posted an
unwriting loss of rupees three not nine
crores versus a loss of rupees
269 crores qoq
the combined ratio declined 130 bps qoq
to
103.2 percent the management believes
this ratio will decline further but be
hundred plus in the next two years the
motor segment continues to form a major
part of the premium collections and
consists of 45 percent of the same
compared to 44 percent in the previous
quarter at rupees
2250 crores calculated while the health
segment is now 22
of total premium compared to similar
levels
sequentially and was up to seven percent
qoq
the contribution of motors tp growth
from the cv segment is slightly higher
this year within the health segment
retail was up by one percent qoq while
in the corporate segment premium growth
was up to 10 percent qoq the company
expects market share in the private car
segments to catch up soon thank you for
watching hi business
you